<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Categories on From the Cardano Frontier</title><link>https://www.frankdelpid.io/categories/</link><description>Recent content in Categories on From the Cardano Frontier</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2021 - Frank DelPidio</copyright><atom:link href="https://www.frankdelpid.io/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MIT Blockchain Course</title><link>https://www.frankdelpid.io/posts/mit-blockchain-course/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 04:06:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.frankdelpid.io/posts/mit-blockchain-course/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In 2018 Gary Gensier, who is the current Chairman of the SEC, taught a business course at MIT about blockchain technology. The course lectures and material are availble to the public through MIT&amp;rsquo;s OpenCourseware. I decided to take the course to learn more about blockchain&amp;rsquo;s potential use cases to change the world of money and finance. A link to the course as well as my notes for each lecture can be found &lt;a href="https://frankdelpidio.notion.site/Blockchain-And-Money-c4bb6486ca66485e958853f3566e8c02">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;h2 id="my-opinion">My Opinion&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The course is a good way to get a broad understanding of blockchain technology, public policy, and potential use cases. The pre lecture readings are a good blend of curated blog posts, government reports, and academic journals. The video lectures provide some interesting debates on the usefullness of blockchain technology (particularly Bitcoin) compared to alternatives.&lt;/p>&lt;p>I believe the course is a good time investment if you want a broad understanding of how blockchain technology will impact society. In the &lt;a href="https://frankdelpidio.notion.site/Week-1-Introduction-1b7828d99f684531849288f23df85890">first lecture study questions&lt;/a> I state that what I wished to learn from the course was possible use cases for blockchain technology, a deeper understanding of its strengths and weaknesses from a first principled approach, and ways to turn its strengths into functioning projects and businesses. The course succeeded by these metrics, and provides a framework for analyzing blockchain projects.&lt;/p>&lt;p>If you are interested in blockchain but don&amp;rsquo;t want to commit to the time investment of 24 lectures, I encourage you to browse the lecture titles listed on &lt;a href="https://frankdelpidio.notion.site/Blockchain-And-Money-c4bb6486ca66485e958853f3566e8c02">my notion page&lt;/a> and click on the topics most interesting to you and read the pre lecture readings. 80 percent of the value comes from doing the readings.&lt;/p>&lt;h2 id="tldr">TL;DR&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The TL;DR for the course can be summed up in my &lt;a href="https://frankdelpidio.notion.site/Week-24-Conclusion-938a31e264e94dda97d6dae7931c2b0d">final lecture notes&lt;/a> which I will repost below:&lt;/p>&lt;h3 id="what-is-blockchain-technology-what-is-money">What is blockchain technology? What is money?&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Blockchain technology is an append only database. It became popular with bitcoin and cryptocurrencies because of the ability for the append only database to be distributed, and Satoshi Nakomoto&amp;rsquo;s paper that described a system for shared consensus on when to append new records to the log.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Money can be defined with three characteristics:&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>A medium of exchange&lt;/li>&lt;li>A store of value&lt;/li>&lt;li>A unit of account&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;h3 id="how-might-blockchain-technology-fit-within-the-world-of-money-and-finance">How might blockchain technology fit within the world of money and finance?&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Blockchain technology could be the database of the world&amp;rsquo;s global currency one day. If Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s vision becomes true, then there will be no central control of money in the world, and a digital decentralized currency will be the basis for all transactions.&lt;/p>&lt;h3 id="how-can-you-best-assess-a-potential-blockchain-project-as-a-catalyst-for-change-a-break-out-app-or-but-another-likely-failed-endeavor">How can you best assess a potential blockchain project as a catalyst for change, a break-out app or but another likely failed endeavor?&lt;/h3>&lt;p>I think I would go back to the checklist I added in the notes of Week 21:&lt;/p>&lt;p>• What is the value creation proposition and ‘pain point’ is being solved?• Which transactions and data needs recording?• Which multiple stakeholders need write and read access to ledgers?• Which costs of verification or networking can be reduced?• What are competitors doing to address similar value propositions or markets?• Why are append only logs and multiple party consensus the best solution?• If permissionless applications, why is native token the best solution?• What are tradeoffs of scalability, performance, privacy, security, &amp;amp; coordination• Can permissioned blockchain or traditional database adequately address use case?• How can broad adoption be realized?• What is the customer interface and how is it better than current interface?&lt;/p>&lt;p>And add the following:&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>Who are the founders/developers driving the project? What are their backgrounds?&lt;/li>&lt;li>What kind of community does this project have?&lt;/li>&lt;li>Do they make decisions that prioritize short term goals or long term goals?&lt;/li>&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>